# Dipanjan Das

Security Researcher SecLab, UCSB

724 Kroeber Walk, Apt. 101 Goleta, California 93117 (805) 728 0706 면 www.dipanjan.in @sherlock

#### Research Interests

My research is directed towards developing novel analysis techniques to uncover vulnerabilities in low-level system software, e.g. operating system kernels and boot-loaders. To work on various exploit mitigation techniques for such targets to improve their practicality is in my future research plan.

#### Education

2016-Present	<b>Ph.D.</b> , <i>University of California</i> , Santa Barbara, <i>GPA - 4.0/4.0</i> . Computer Security, advised by Prof. Giovanni Vigna & Prof. Christopher Kruegel
2013-2015	M.Tech., Indian Institute of Technology, Madras, GPA – 8.81/10.0. Computer Science & Engineering, advised by Prof. PanduRangan Chandrasekaran
2006-2010	<b>B.Tech.</b> , <i>Institute of Engineering &amp; Management</i> , Kolkata, <i>GPA – 8.92/10.0</i> .

# **Professional Experience**

Computer Science & Engineering

2010-2012	Assistant Systems Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), Kolkata, India.
2012-2013	Scientist Engineer - SC, Gazetted Officer, Class 'A', Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO), Vikram Sarabhai Research Centre (VSSC), Trivandrum, India.

 To develop SPARCSIM, an instruction set simulator for a customized SPARC v8 based processor to be used on-board of next generation launch vehicles.

2013-2015 Teaching Assistant, Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Madras, India.

2015-2015 Software Developer, BrowserStack, Mumbai, India.

2015-2016 Post-Graduate Research Intern, National University of Singapore, Singapore.

Automatic patching of closed-source programs

2017-2017 **Interim Engineering Intern**, *Qualcomm Technologies*, *Inc*, San Diego.

• Developing a memory safe API in Rust to be used by Qualcomm drivers

Developing an off-device fuzzing platform for a WLAN driver

2020-2020 Research Intern, University of Minnesota (Prof. Kangjie Lu), Minneapolis.

Kernel fuzzing technique to trigger order-inconsistency bugs

#### **Publications**

- N. Redini, A. Continella, D. Das, G. D. Pasquale, A. Machiry, A. Bianchi, C. Kruegel, and G. Vigna, "Diane: Identifying fuzzing triggers in apps to generate under-constrained inputs for iot devices," in 42nd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P), 2021.
- D. Song, F. Hetzelt, D. Das, C. Spensky, Y. Na, S. Volckaert, G. Vigna, C. Kruegel, J. P. Seifert, and M. Franz, "Periscope: An effective probing and fuzzing framework for the hardware-os boundary," in BlackHat USA, 2019.
- D. Song, F. Hetzelt, D. Das, C. Spensky, Y. Na, S. Volckaert, G. Vigna, C. Kruegel, J. P. Seifert, and M. Franz, "Periscope: An effective probing and fuzzing framework for the hardware-os boundary," in 26th Annual Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), This work was presented in Qualcomm Product Security Summit (QPSS), San Diego, CA, May 2019.

- Was among the top 10 finalists in Applied Research Competition, CSAW, November 2019, 2019.
- [4] N. Redini, A. Machiry, **D. Das**, Y. Fratantonio, A. Bianchi, E. Gustafson, Y. Shoshitaishvili, G. Vigna, and C. Kruegel, "Bootstomp: On the security of bootloaders in mobile devices," in *34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3)*, 2017.
- [3] N. Redini, A. Machiry, **D. Das**, Y. Fratantonio, A. Bianchi, E. Gustafson, Y. Shoshitaishvili, G. Vigna, and C. Kruegel, "Bootstomp: On the security of bootloaders in mobile devices," in *26th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX)*, 2017.
- [2] P. Bose, **D. Das**, and C. P. Rangan, "Constant size ring signature without random oracle," in 20th Australasian Conference on Information Security and Privacy (ACISP), 2015.
- [1] **D. Das**, P. Bose, S. S. Vivek, S. S. D. Selvi, and C. P. Rangan, *An identity based encryption scheme resilient to ram scraper like malware attacks*, Cryptology ePrint Archive, Report 2015/1156, 2015.

#### **Professional Achievements**

- Reported vulnerabilities CVE-2018-14745, CVE-2018-14852, CVE-2018-14853, CVE-2018-14854, CVE-2018-14855, CVE-2018-14856 to Samsung and CVE-2018-11947, CVE-2018-11902 to Qualcomm.
- Appears in CodeAurora Hall-of-Fame (2018) and Samsung Android Security Updates (August 2018).
- o Invited to Qualcomm Vulnerability Rewards Program at HackerOne (September 2018).

## **Scholastic Achievements**

- $\circ$  Stood  $29^{th}$  in  $X^{th}$  standard and  $16^{th}$  in  $XII^{th}$  state board examinations.
- ${\color{blue} \circ}$  Awarded by *Viren J. Shah*, ex-governor of West Bengal, at his residence, Raj Bhawan, for  $10^{th}$  rank in Kolkata zone in  $X^{th}$  standard board examination.
- Secured all India rank 106 among 2, 24, 160 candidates in GATE 2013.
- $\circ$  Secured all India rank 11 and 20 among 12,227 and 10,737 candidates in Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) entrance examination 2011 and 2014 respectively.

#### Honors & Awards

- Received National Merit Scholarship twice from Ministry of Human Resource and Development (MHRD), Government of India for securing  $29^{th}$  position in  $X^{th}$  standard and  $16^{th}$  position in  $XII^{th}$  state board examinations.
- Received Presidential Graduate Fellowship at National University of Singapore (NUS).
- Received scholarship from *Ministry of Human Resource and Development* (MHRD), Government of India for pursuing M.Tech. at IIT, Madras.

### **Professional Services**

- Member of Shellphish Capture-The-Flag (CTF) team. Participated in DEFCON CTF Finals in the year 2017, 2018 and 2019.
- Member of the organizing team of UCSB iCTF security competition in the year 2017 and 2018.
- Shadow Program Committee member of IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P) 2021 and Extended Review Committee member of EuroSys 2021 conferences.

## Media Coverage

- Sep 2017 **ZDNet**, Android security: Multiple bootloader bugs found in major chipset vendors' code, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 The Register, Boffins hijack bootloaders for fun and games on Android, for BootStomp [3].

- Sep 2017 **The Hacker News**, *Mobile Bootloaders From Top Manufacturers Found Vulnerable to Persistent Threats*, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 NowSecure, Android bootloader security and BootStomp: A Primer, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 **Washington Center for CyberSecurity**, *BootStomp: Useful Tool in Researching Bootloaders*, for BootStomp [3].
- Aug 2017 PenTestIT, BootStomp: Find Mobile Device Bootloader Vulnerabilities, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 **ProgrammerSought**, BootStomp: About the bootloader security of mobile devices 6 BootStomp, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 SecurityWeek, Multiple Vulnerabilities Found in Mobile Bootloaders, for BootStomp [3].
- Dec 2017 **Pentest Tools**, *BootStomp A Bootloader Vulnerability Finder*, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 **NowSecure**, *Android bootloader security and BootStomp: A Primer*, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 **HebergementWebs**, *Experts discovered zero day flaws in Android bootloaders*, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 **Security Affairs**, https://securityaffairs.co/wordpress/62762/mobile-2/bootstomp-bootloaders-flaws.html, for BootStomp [3].
- Sep 2017 Hackers Online Club, BootStomp: An Android boot-loader Bug Finder, for BootStomp [3].
- Feb 2018 **Quantus**, BootStomp Find Android Bootloader Vulnerabilities, for BootStomp [3].